Yogesh Gupta

LinkedIn: vogesh-gupta-117495169

Portfolio: https://yogeshportfolio.vercel.app/ Github: https://github.com/yogesh8633

New Delhi, India

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Mobile: +91 9711708633

Email: yogeshg9711@gmail.com

Software Engineer-Frontend at OCPL TECH. I have more than 2.3 years of experience in designing and development of web applications. Expertise in full-stack development and project management

HIGHLIGHTS

Key Early Contributor at OCPL:

Joined as the second employee at OCPL and played a pivotal role in the company's growth from its inception. Contributed to expanding the client base to over 10+ CRM and website clients and helped grow the team to more than 30 members.

- Leadership experience in Celect Placement Cell at Ramanujan College from 2021-22
- Awarded with PK kaul Memorial Scholarship in First Year of College
- Awarded with prize money for being FIRST in First Year Of College
- C/C++
- Javascript
- NodeJS
- ReactIS
- Bootstrap
- Framer Motion
- SASS, CSS
- POSTMAN
- VS Code
- Dapps
- Blockchain
- Github, Gitlab
- IPFS
- MongoDB, SQL

WORK EXPERIENCE

OCPL TECH | Software Engineer-Frontend

Delhi Aug 2022 - present

- Lead developer and solution designer for complex projects
- My responsibilities included designing solutions for the projects. Collaborating with the team of developers. I ensured the successful implementation of the proposed solutions.
- From Backend to Frontend, from client meetings to delivery. I have handled each and every thing here.
- Developed new features and enhancements in fast-paced environments
- Researched and identified software solutions to meet customer needs and objectives.
- Conducted code reviews to maintain quality and performance standards
- TechStack: ReactJs, Javascript, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML, SCSS, Next.js, NodeJS

SARVVID AI | Frontend Developer

Delhi Jun 2022 - Aug 2022

- Worked as a developer to built blockchain based products for the company, Learnt above IPFS and overview of blockchain.
- Tech Stack: ReactJS, CSS, IPFS, Blockchain.
- Collaborated with backend developers to ensure seamless integration of frontend and backend components.
- Developed reusable components for scalability
- worked with backend developers to implement integrations with server side technologies.

Hatke Attire | Web Developer

Delhi

Sept 2021 - Nov 2021

- Proficient in developing responsive, cross browser compatible websites
- Excellent communications and collaboration skills with other developers and non technical staff.
- Experienced in integrating with RESTful APIs and backend Services

SOFT SKILLS

Communication, Problem-Solving, Attention to Detail, Collaboration, Adaptability, Time Management, Creativity, Empathy, Teamwork

EDUCATION

Ramanujan College, Delhi University Bachelor Degree Software Development, CGPA: 9.05

Delhi 2019-2022

M.D.H International School

XII; Percentage: 86%

Delhi

June 2018